<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Code Ramblings - Peter Kazarinoff</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/peter-kazarinoff.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2017-09-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>second_post</title><link href="/second_post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-09-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Peter Kazarinoff</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-09-17:/second_post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Second blog post. Yah hoo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VoidyBootstrap&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version 2.1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Bootstrap 3 blog theme for the Pelican static site generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VoidyBootstrap is a Pelican theme that aims to be mobile friendly, responsive, flexible and easily customisable. It can be used in single column mode, or responsive 2 column mode with …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Second blog post. Yah hoo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VoidyBootstrap&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version 2.1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Bootstrap 3 blog theme for the Pelican static site generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VoidyBootstrap is a Pelican theme that aims to be mobile friendly, responsive, flexible and easily customisable. It can be used in single column mode, or responsive 2 column mode with sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the theme provides lots of customisation options, care has been taken to make it usable right out of the box with minimal configuration and sensible defaults -- albeit with the ubiquitous Bootstrap look and feel. But that's kind of the idea with this theme -- start with bog standard Bootstrap, then customise as much or as little as you like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On larger screens, with the sidebar enabled, you get a clean and responsive 2 column layout. At the top there's a navbar containing page links, and jumbotron area. The default sidebar has category links and optional tag-cloud. Font Awesome 4 is used for icons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VoidyBootstrap is functional but deliberately minimal in terms of design. It can be used as is, if your design need are modest and all you want is basic theme that "just works", with all the common features you'd expect from a blog theme. But for those who do want to tinker and customise, it can be used as a starting point for creating custom Bootstrap-based websites. This theme has many features designed to facilitate creating a custom design on top of the default Bootstrap base it provides. Regardless of whether you use few or many of the customisation features provided, what you get is a carefully crafted Pelican theme that tries to accommodate common blogging needs and provide ways to easily accomplish common customisations. It strives to be as minimal, flexible and unopinionated as possible, while still being as usable and simple as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customised CSS, JavaScript and other modifications can be easily incorporated using configuration settings, and content can be added to the base layout (without modifying existing templates) by strategically adding template fragments.
Installation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clone this repo, then in your pelicanconf.py set the THEME variable to point to it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THEME = 'path/to/voidy-bootstrap/'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the box what you get is the stock standard Bootstrap 3 look and feel. To customise things see below.
Example Settings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these are optional, but here is a basic example of common settings you might want to configure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following should be set in pelicanconf.py:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SITESUBTITLE ='Sub-title that goes underneath site name in jumbotron.'
SITETAG = "Text that's displayed in the title on the home page."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Extra stylesheets, for bootstrap overrides or additional styling.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;STYLESHEET_FILES = ("pygment.css", "voidybootstrap.css",)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Put taglist at end of articles, and use the default sharing button implementation.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CUSTOM_ARTICLE_FOOTERS = ("taglist.html", "sharing.html", )
CUSTOM_SCRIPTS_ARTICLE = "sharing_scripts.html"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Default sidebar template. Omit this setting for single column mode without sidebar.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIDEBAR = "sidebar.html"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SOCIAL = (('Google+', 'http://plus.google.com/userid',
         'fa fa-google-plus-square fa-fw fa-lg'),
        ('Twitter', 'https://twitter.com/username',
         'fa fa-twitter-square fa-fw fa-lg'),
        ('LinkedIn', 'http://linkedin-url',
         'fa fa-linkedin-square fa-fw fa-lg'),
        ('BitBucket', 'http://bitbucket.org/username',
         'fa fa-bitbucket-square fa-fw fa-lg'),
        ('GitHub', 'http://github.com/username',
         'fa fa-github-square fa-fw fa-lg'),
        )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are probably better suited for publishconf.py:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FEED_DOMAIN = SITEURL
FEED_ALL_ATOM = 'feeds/all.atom.xml'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DISQUS_SITENAME = "disqussitename"
GOOGLE_ANALYTICS = "UA-xxxxxxxxxx"
GOOGLE_ANALYTICS_SITEID = "gasiteid"
TWITTER_USERNAME = "twitterusername"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic Configuration and Customisation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default all required CSS and JavaScript files are downloaded from CDNs. Intentionally little is supplied in the theme's static/css. Just a pygment.css file, and a sample css file (voidybootstrap.css) with very minimal styling is provided as a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simplest way to customise things is to override the standard Bootstrap styles as necessary. The theme intentionally avoids loading any additional stylesheets by default, but this can easily be done by using the STYLESHEET_FILES setting. STYLESHEET_FILES is a list for specifying additional stylesheets that will be loaded by the base.html template after the main Bootstrap CSS file. Place any CSS stylesheet files you may require in the static/css directory and add the filenames to the STYLESHEET_FILES setting in pelicanconf.py&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you've placed your own CSS styling in a stylesheet called custom.css (possibly using voidybootstrap.css as a starting point), then you would need something like this in your pelicanconf.py:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;STYLESHEET_FILES = ("pygment.css", "custom.css",)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Custom Bootstrap&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an alternative, or in addition, you can easily replace the standard Bootstrap file with a customised one. The BOOTSTRAP_STYLESHEET setting is provided for this. The default behaviour -- if this variable is not set -- is that a standard bootstrap.min.css will be used from a CDN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use a different (i.e. customised) Bootstrap stylesheet, set BOOTSTRAP_STYLESHEET to the filename of a stylesheet to use instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could be a customised Bootstrap stylesheet compiled manually from the Bootstrap source files, or perhaps one obtained from an online source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, you could use the Bootstrap customizer to create your own customised Bootstrap CSS file. Place that file in static/css and set BOOTSTRAP_STYLESHEET to its filename.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, a Bootswatch theme can be easily integrated. Select a theme and download the files. Place all the necessary CSS files in static/css. Set BOOTSTRAP_STYLESHEET to the filename of the main Bootstrap CSS file, and specify any additional CSS files in the STYLESHEET_FILES list.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>third_post</title><link href="/third_post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-11T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-09-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Peter Kazarinoff</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-09-11:/third_post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;To open a raspberry pi&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;To open a raspberry pi&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>first_post</title><link href="/first_post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Peter Kazarinoff</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-08-14:/first_post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hellow world from the pelican blog post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is some code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;python&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;all&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;A&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;34&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;A&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;All&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;reare&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;tr&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;save&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;mysave&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So that was a code section. Let's see what happens&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hellow world from the pelican blog post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is some code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;python&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;all&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;A&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;34&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;A&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;All&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;reare&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;tr&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;save&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;mysave&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So that was a code section. Let's see what happens&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>